And two percent of you have a tendency to extreme profanity.
Forty-six percent of you I could link to a business,
So I ran a little scan.
So something for you to think about:
XYZ Employee network.
I was relatively inhibited compared to the cybercriminals,
As we adopt these new applications and mobile devices,
This isn't an exact science, but it gets pretty accurate.
who wouldn't be so concerned by law,
as we play with these shiny new toys,
how much are we trading off convenience
things start to happen on the computer on their own,
for privacy and security?
usually a bad sign.
Next time you install something,
This would, of course, normally happen
In the U.K., a 60 percent reduction since 2003,
look at the settings and ask yourself,
in a couple of seconds, really, really quickly,
and there are similar statistics all over the world.
"Is this information that I want to share?
but I've kind of slowed it down
We also need to think about the legal issues in this area.
Would someone be able to abuse it?"
so you can actually see the attack occurring.
The cybercriminals I talked about,
Malware is very boring otherwise.
despite theft of millions of dollars,
the attackers can get with such a simple operation?
So this is writing out the malicious code,
actually still haven't been arrested,
Let me show you how most malware
and a few seconds later, on the left-hand side,
and at this point possibly never will.
is now distributed today.
you'll see the attacker's screen get some interesting new text.
find these simple best practices,
Most laws are national in their implementation,
What I'm going to do is open up a website
find out how to update and patch your computer.
despite cybercrime conventions, where the Internet
that I wrote.
Get a secure password.
is borderless and international by definition.
It's a terrible website. It's got really awful graphics.
Make sure you use a different password
And it's got a comments section here
on each of your sites and services online.
I'm going to open up the web browser
where we can submit comments to the website.
Find these resources. Apply them.
and browse to my website,
Many of you will have used something a bit like this before.
The Internet is a fantastic resource
www.incrediblyhacked.com.
Unfortunately, when this was implemented,
for business, for political expression,
Notice that after a couple of seconds,
for art and for learning.
I get redirected.
Help me and the security community
That website address at the top there,
which you can just about see, microshaft.com,
Now I liked it better when viruses were free.
the browser crashes as it hits one of these exploit packs,
(Laughter)
and up pops fake antivirus.
People now pay cybercriminals money
This is a virus pretending to look like antivirus software,
to run viruses,
which I find utterly bizarre.
in malware and hacking looks like.
So anyway, let me change pace a little bit.
So today, computer viruses and trojans,
Chasing 250,000 pieces of malware a day
designed to do everything from stealing data
An interesting feature of lots of modern smartphones
like many of you might use.
is a massive challenge,
to watching you in your webcam
is that when you take a photo,
At the top, you'll notice a section of source code.
and those numbers are only growing
to the theft of billions of dollars.
it embeds GPS data about where that photo was taken.
What this would do is send the cybercriminals
directly in proportion to the length of my stress line, you'll note here.
Some malicious code today goes as far
In fact, I've been spending a lot of time
a text message every day telling them how much money
as targeting power, utilities and infrastructure.
on Internet dating sites recently,
they'd made that day,
are small business websites getting infected.
Let me give you a quick snapshot
obviously for research purposes,
so a kind of cybercriminal billings report, if you will.
Today's cybercriminal, what do they look like?
of what malicious code is capable of today.
and I've noticed that about 60 percent
If you look closely, you'll notice a series
Well, many of you have the image, don't you,
Right now, every second, eight new users
for a BMW that one of our cybercriminals is selling,
of the profile pictures on Internet dating sites
of what are Russian telephone numbers.
of the spotty teenager sitting in a basement,
on the other side an advert for the sale of sphynx kittens.
contain the GPS coordinates of where the photo was taken,
Now that's obviously interesting,
hacking away for notoriety.
One of these was more stereotypical for me.
which is kind of scary
because that gives us a way of finding our cybercriminals.
But actually today, cybercriminals
A little more searching, and here's our cybercriminal.
are wonderfully professional and organized.
Imagine, these are hardened cybercriminals
Not only that, we are providing a short-term-to-long-term
In fact, they have product adverts.
sharing information scarcely.
DDOS service or scheduled attack,
You can go online and buy a hacking service
Imagine what you could find
starting five dollars per hour for small personal websites
to knock your business competitor offline.
can break our security even when we do the right things.
about each of the people in this room.
to 10 to 50 dollars per hour.
This is MobSoft, one of the companies
A bit more searching through the profile
James Lyne: Now, I did actually pay
that this cybercriminal gang owned,
and there's a photo of their office.
one of these cybercriminals to attack my own website.
I'm going to be showing some of the cybercriminals'
and an interesting thing about MobSoft
Things got a bit tricky when I tried to expense it at the company.
latest and nastiest creations.
is the 50-percent owner of this
This is the market leader in malware distribution,
Turns out that's not cool.
So basically, please don't go and download
posted a job advert,
the Black Hole Exploit Pack,
But regardless, it's amazing how many products
any of the viruses that I show you.
and this job advert matched one of the telephone numbers
responsible for nearly one third of malware distribution
and services are available now to cybercriminals.
Some of you might be wondering what a cybersecurity specialist looks like,
Now you're probably wondering what happened to these guys.
from the code earlier.
in the last couple of quarters.
Let me come back to that in just a minute.
This woman was Maria,
It comes with technical installation guides,
and I thought I'd give you a quick insight
I want to change pace to one last little demonstration,
and Maria is the wife of one of our cybercriminals.
video setup routines,
into my career so far.
a technique that is wonderfully simple and basic,
and get this, technical support.
It's a pretty accurate description.
but is interesting in exposing how much information
that says something like, "Hi, I'm a Nigerian banker,
You can email the cybercriminals and they'll tell you
This is what someone that specializes
we're all giving away,
and I'd like to give you 53 billion dollars
how to set up your illegal hacking server.
and it's relevant because it applies to us as a TED audience.
because I like your face."
So let me show you what malicious code looks like today.
Seven hundred and sixty-one of you I could identify a hotel you'd been to recently,
and here you can see my mobile device.
This is normally when people start kind of shuffling in their pockets
Or funnycats.exe, which rumor has it
absolutely with pinpoint precision somewhere on the globe.
Okay? So you can see a list of wireless networks.
trying to turn their phones onto airplane mode desperately.
was quite successful in China's recent campaign against America.
Two hundred and thirty-four of you, well, I know where you live.
TEDAttendees, HyattLB. Where do you think I'm staying?
Many of you all know about the concept
Now there are many ways you can get infected.
Your wireless network name is so unique
My home network, PrettyFlyForAWifi,
I want to show you a couple of my favorites.
that I was able to pinpoint it
which I think is a great name.
Awww.
This is a little USB key.
using data available openly on the Internet
Sophos_Visitors, SANSEMEA, companies I work with.
Or, in my case, awkward and pathetic.
Now how do you get a USB key to run in a business?
with no hacking or clever, clever tricks.
Loganwifi, that's in Boston. HiltonLondon.
So imagine this scenario: I walk into one of your businesses,
Well, you could try looking really cute.
We also need to think very carefully
And I should mention as well that
CIASurveillanceVan.
looking very awkward and pathetic, with a copy of my C.V.
about how we develop our future talent pool.
some of you do use your names,
We called it that at one of our conferences
which I've covered in coffee,
You see, technology's changing at a staggering rate,
"James Lyne's iPhone," for example.
because we thought that would freak people out,
and I ask the receptionist to plug in this USB key
and that 250,000 pieces of malware
and print me a new one.
won't stay the same for long.
Now if I place the mouse cursor over it,
So let's have a look here on my victim computer.
There's a very concerning trend
this is what we call a command prompt,
What I'm going to do is plug in the USB key.
that whilst many people coming out of schools now
and using this we can navigate around the computer.
After a couple of seconds,
Countries do not agree, which makes this area
are much more technology-savvy, they know how to use technology,
We can access your documents, your data.
exceptionally challenging from a legal perspective.
fewer and fewer people are following the feeder subjects
You can turn on the webcam.
But my biggest ask is this:
to know how that technology works under the covers.
That can be very embarrassing.
You see, you're going to leave here
Or just to really prove a point,
and you're going to see some astonishing stories in the news.
the developer was slightly inebriated
we can launch programs like my personal favorite,
You're going to read about malware doing incredible
and managed to forget
the Windows Calculator.
and terrifying, scary things.
all of the secure coding practices he had learned.
So isn't it amazing how much control
make life much, much more difficult
However, 99 percent of it works
So let's imagine that our attacker,
for cybercriminals.
because people fail to do the basics.
called Evil Hacker just for comedy value,
Thank you.
So my ask is this: Go online,
inserts something a little nasty.
(Applause)
This is a script.
and it will go through and it will scan the system,
It's code which will be interpreted on the webpage.
have a look at what its popping up here.
So I'm going to submit this post,
It creates some very serious alerts.
and then, on my victim computer,
Oh look, a child porn proxy server.
We really should clean that up.
What's really insulting about this is
not only does it provide the attackers with access to your data,
Down below, highlighted in red,
So I want to talk to you briefly
but when the scan finishes, they tell you
in the other section of source code,
about a group of hackers we tracked for a year
in order to clean up the fake viruses,
is this bit "leded:leded."
and actually found --
you have to register the product.
That's a username,
and this is a rare treat in our job.
kind of like you might have on Twitter.
Now this was a cross-industry collaboration,
are joining the Internet.
So let's take this a little further.
people from Facebook, independent researchers,
Today, we will see 250,000 individual new computer viruses.
There are a few other interesting pieces
guys from Sophos.
We will see 30,000 new infected websites.
because you wouldn't give out your home address
the cybercriminals had uploaded.
So here we have a couple of documents
And, just to kind of tear down a myth here,
to lots of strangers,
Lots of you here will use smartphones
which our cybercriminals had uploaded
lots of people think that when you get infected
but we're happy to give away our GPS coordinates
to take photos and post them from the conference.
to a cloud service, kind of like Dropbox or SkyDrive,
with a computer virus, it's because you went to a porn site.
to plus or minus 15 meters.
Right? Well, actually, statistically speaking,
And our cybercriminals had done the same thing.
Check out this one I found.
if you only visit porn sites, you're safer.
So here's a photo which resolves to St. Petersburg.
(Video) Man: So you're here for one reason,
People normally write that down, by the way. (Laughter)
We then deploy the incredibly advanced hacking tool.
and that reason is
Actually, about 80 percent of these
They were working on the third floor.
We used Google.
because you need your business competitors,
And you can also see some photos
Using the email address, the telephone number
rivals, haters, or whatever the reason is, or who,
from his business companion
and the GPS data, on the left you see an advert
they are to go down.
where he has a taste in a certain kind of image.
Well you, my friend, you've came to the right place.
It turns out he's a member of the Russian Adult Webmasters Federation.
For example, this testing platform,
If you want your business competitors to go down,
But this is where our investigation starts to slow down.
which enables the cybercriminals
well, they can.
The cybercriminals have locked down their profiles quite well.
to test the quality of their viruses
If you want your rivals to go offline, well, they will.
And it's kind of like she went into her social media settings
And herein is the greatest lesson
before they release them on the world.
and clicked on every option imaginable
of social media and mobile devices for all of us right now.
For a small fee, they can upload it
to make herself really, really insecure.
Our friends, our families and our colleagues
and make sure everything is good.
By the end of the investigation,
But it goes further.
where you can read the full 27-page report at that link,
What I've got here is two systems,
Cybercriminals now have crime packs
we had photos of the cybercriminals,
an attacker, which I've made look all Matrix-y and scary,
with business intelligence reporting dashboards
even the office Christmas party
and a victim, which you might recognize from home or work.
to manage the distribution of their malicious code.
which is quite fun.
of scanning for wireless networks.
when they were out on an outing.
Now normally, these would be on different sides
This is how geeks party.
You do it every time you take out your iPhone or your Blackberry
That's right, cybercriminals do have Christmas parties,
of the planet or of the Internet,
So let's make this a little bit more interesting.
and connect to something like TEDAttendees.
as it turns out.
but I've put them side by side
Let's talk about you.
But what you might not know
because it makes things much more interesting.
Twenty-three percent of you have been to Starbucks
is that you're also beaming out a list of networks
Now, there are many ways you can get infected.
recently and used the wireless network.
you've previously connected to,
You will have come in contact with some of them.
Things get more interesting.
even when you're not using wireless actively.
Maybe some of you have received an email